Now if you call your friend and you just say Hey do you want to eat now.
现在，如果你打电话给你的朋友，你只是说嘿，你现在想吃吗。
It's not a terrible thing but usually when you call your friend you don't just say directly what you
这不是一件可怕的事情，但通常当你打电话给你的朋友时，你不会直接说出你的意思
want.
想。
You need to have a little bit of free chat a little bit of small talk especially if you haven't talked
你需要有一点免费的闲聊，特别是如果你还没有说话的话
to your friend in a little while.
一会儿给你的朋友。
So there are some common questions that we ask in this sort of situation and many many other situations
因此，在这种情况和许多其他情况下，我们会提出一些常见问题
that we can use to catch up.
我们可以用它来赶上。
Which means to talk about things you haven't talked about since you last saw each other or just have
这意味着谈论自从你们上次见面或刚刚见面以来没有谈过的事情
a bit of what we would call small talk.
有点我们称之为闲聊的东西。
So here are the common questions that we use.
所以这里是我们使用的常见问题。
And there are more.
还有更多。
But here are some really common ones.
但这里有一些非常常见的。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
Hey what's up.
嘿，怎么了。
Now what does what's up really mean.
现在什么是真正的意思。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
Actually means not how are you but what are you doing.
实际上意味着不是你好吗，而是你在做什么。
How are you.
你好吗。
It's different than what's up.
这与现在的情况不同。
Let's just be clear about that.
让我们清楚一点。
OK.
好的。
You say what's up.
你说怎么回事。
It means either.
这意味着要么。
What are you doing right now.
你现在在做什么。
What's wrong.
怎么了。
There's a problem.
有问题。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
What happened.
发生了什么。
Right.
正确的。
There's a problem or sometimes it means nothing.
有问题，或者有时没有任何意义。
Often what's up is used as a phrase in situations like this.
在这样的情况下，经常会用what's up 作为短语。
You're in the office and you pass your coworker and your coworker goes Hey.
你在办公室，你经过你的同事，你的同事说嘿。
And you go Hey what's up in that case sometimes it's just like saying hi or hello.
你去嘿，在那种情况下发生了什么有时就像打个招呼或你好。
You can answer it but usually when people answer it in that kind of situation it's like nothing not
你可以回答它，但通常当人们在那种情况下回答它时，就像什么都没有
much.
很多。
Nothing.
没有什么。
Not much these are common answers to what's up and then usually people will say you butt in the phone
这些不是什么常见的答案，然后通常人们会说你在电话里打屁股
call situation.
通话情况。
You could actually say what you're doing.
你实际上可以说你在做什么。
So they call you and say oh hey hey what's up.
所以他们打电话给你，说哦，嘿嘿，怎么了。
I'm just sitting at home watching TV or actually I'm doing some homework or I'm about to go to work.
我只是坐在家里看电视，或者实际上我正在做一些功课，或者我正要上班。
You can say what you're doing OK now that's different than how are you.
你可以说你现在做得很好，这与你现在的情况不同。
If someone says How are you.
如果有人说你好吗。
Obviously you can say I'm good I'm OK I'm great I'm fine right.
很明显，你可以说我很好，我很好，我很好，我很好。
But we don't even need to go into that one because it's it's so basic.
但我们甚至不需要进入那个，因为它是如此基础。
However we can look at this one.
不过我们可以看看这个。
How's it going.
怎么样了。
How is it going.
最近好吗。
That means how are you.
这意味着你好吗。
It's exactly the same as how are you.
这和你怎么样是完全一样的。
Except we say How's it going.
除了我们说进展如何。
What is it.
它是什么。
It's like your your situation.
跟你的情况一样。
Right.
正确的。
So when you answer we often then use it to answer it's going all right.
因此，当您回答时，我们经常使用它来回答，一切正常。
It's going fine it's going great.
一切顺利，一切顺利。
Instead of saying I'm great I'm all right.
与其说我很棒，不如说我很好。
I'm fine.
我很好。
But again basically it's the same thing.
但基本上它还是一样的。
How have you been.
你最近怎么样。
Now we've learned.
现在我们已经学会了。
Have you been.
你去过吗。
Right.
正确的。
We've learned that this means including now and also recently.
我们了解到，这意味着包括现在和最近。
Right including now and also recently.
包括现在和最近。
So let's say I haven't seen you in two weeks and I say How have you been.
所以假设我已经两周没见到你了，我会说你好吗。
When you answer me you might talk about some of the things that have happened in the last two weeks
当你回答我时，你可能会谈论过去两周发生的一些事情
because I haven't talked to you since then.
因为从那以后我没有和你说过话。
So if I say how do you mean you can say Yeah I've been.
所以，如果我说你是什么意思，你可以说是的，我去过。
Same same grammar.
同样的语法。
Usually the answer matches the question I've been pretty well although I've been quite busy recently
通常答案与我一直很好的问题相匹配，尽管我最近很忙
with work or I've been okay.
工作或我一直很好。
Last week I got a cold and I'm still I'm still recovering but cold.
上周我感冒了，我还在恢复中，但感冒了。
Okay so here.
好的，这里。
Have you been.
你去过吗。
It's not just now it's over time until now.
不只是现在，直到现在。
And we often then we'll add something after it first you answer I've been pretty well and then you can
我们经常会在它之后添加一些东西，首先你回答我一直很好，然后你可以
add something else.
添加其他内容。
I just bought a new car.
我刚买了一辆新车。
I've been sick recently.
我最近病了。
I'm going to Florida next week.
我下周要去佛罗里达。
Whatever.
任何。
OK.
好的。
How about how have things been.
事情怎么样了。
How have things been.
情况如何。
Again.
再次。
This is pretty much the same except again the answer the answer usually matches the question.
这几乎相同，除了答案通常与问题相匹配。
So how have things been.
那么事情进展如何。
Things have been OK.
一切都还好。
Things have been great.
事情已经很棒了。
Things have been fantastic.
事情太棒了。
Things have been all right.
一切都很好。
It's the same thing.
这是同一件事。
It just looks different.
它只是看起来不同。
Sort of like this one.
有点像这个。
How's it going is the same as how are you right.
进展如何与你如何正确是一样的。
Actually there are only a couple of questions but they take different forms and the answer usually matches
实际上只有几个问题，但它们采取不同的形式，答案通常匹配
the question which is important to keep in mind.
需要牢记的重要问题。
Sometimes instead of what's up you hear what's going on.
有时，您听到的不是正在发生的事情。
It's the same thing.
这是同一件事。
Basically what are you up to.
基本上你在做什么。
Sometimes we hear up to up to going on what's going on.
有时，我们最多听到正在发生的事情。
What are you doing.
你在干什么。
What are you up to.
你要做什么。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
What are you doing.
你在干什么。
Pretty much all the same.
几乎都一样。
And to answer this after you say for example what's up.
并在你说例如发生了什么之后回答这个问题。
Oh not much.
哦，不多。
Just watching some youtube videos.
只是看一些youtube视频。
Then you'll say you.
那你就说你。
How about you.
你呢。
You asked the same question back you.
你问了同样的问题。
That means I'm asking you the same question.
这意味着我问你同样的问题。
You don't have to.
你不必。
You could say another question.
你可以说另一个问题。
How have you been.
你最近怎么样。
I've been pretty well.
我过得很好。
I was sick last week but I'm doing pretty well now.
我上周病了，但我现在过得很好。
Although next week I have a big exam.
虽然下周我有一场大考试。
This is small talk.
这是闲聊。
Just talk about things that have been going on and things you're doing now for maybe a minute.
只谈谈一直在发生的事情和你现在正在做的事情，也许会花一分钟时间。
And it's not really strict it should be very casual and you should have some things to talk about because
而且它不是很严格，应该很随意，你应该有一些事情要谈，因为
you're friends.
你们是朋友。
So then once you've done a little bit of small talk.
所以，一旦你做了一点闲聊。
One thing that people will often do especially on a phone call is to ask Are you busy now this.
人们在打电话时经常会做的一件事是问你现在忙吗？
Are you busy can often mean and usually means right now in this moment or are you in the middle of anything
你忙通常意味着并且通常意味着此时此刻，或者你在任何事情的中间
or are you free to talk.
或者你有空说话。
Am I interrupting anything so I'm trying to get a feeling for whether or not my phone call is bothering
我是不是打断了任何事情，所以我试图了解我的电话是否打扰
you.
你。
Is my phone call causing you to have to stop doing something and actually you're very busy and you don't
我的电话是不是让你不得不停止做某事而实际上你很忙而你没有
really want to talk to me now.
真的很想说话现在给我。
OK.
好的。
Are you busy.
你忙吗。
No I'm not busy.
不，我不忙。
I'm free.
我自由了。
Are you busy.
你忙吗。
Yeah I'm a little bit busy now.
是的，我现在有点忙。
OK.
好的。
Are you in the middle of anything.
你在任何事情的中间。
I should be middle sorry.
我应该是中间对不起。
That's an owl.
那是一只猫头鹰。
Are you in the middle of anything.
你在任何事情的中间。
No I'm not.
不，我不是。
I'm free in the middle of something.
我在做某事时有空。
I'm in the middle of something means I'm kind of busy.
我在做某事意味着我有点忙。
Are you in the middle of something.
你是不是在做某事。
Are you in the middle of anything.
你在任何事情的中间。
No I'm free.
不，我有空。
OK.
好的。
Are you free to talk.
你有空说话吗。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm free.
我自由了。
No not right now.
不，现在不行。
I'm a little bit busy.
我有点忙。
I'm kind of in the middle of something to make things sound softer we often add kind of and a bit so
我正在做一些事情来让声音听起来更柔和，我们经常添加一些这样的东西
we can say for example I'm kind of in the middle of something.
我们可以说，例如，我有点在做某事。
I'm kind of busy right now or I'm a bit busy right now.
我现在有点忙，或者我现在有点忙。
I'm a bit busy right now.
我现在有点忙。
I'm a bit tied up right now tied up means like you're tied up you can't do anything because you're busy.
我现在有点被束缚了 束缚意味着你被束缚了，因为你很忙，所以你什么都做不了。
OK I'm a bit tied up right now.
好吧，我现在有点紧张。
I'm kind of tied up right now.
我现在有点束缚。
I'm a bit busy at the moment.
我现在有点忙。
Am I interrupting anything interrupt means to stop somebody from doing something.
我在打断任何事情吗？打断意味着阻止某人做某事。
No you're not interrupting anything.
不，你没有打扰任何事情。
I'm free.
我自由了。
I can talk.
我可以说话。
No I can talk.
不，我可以说话。
Am I interrupting anything.
我有没有打断什么。
I am a little bit busy right now.
我现在有点忙。
So if you are busy What can you do.
所以如果你很忙你能做什么。
Should you just say bye.
你是否应该说再见。
No of course not.
不，当然不是。
You could say Can I call you back.
你可以说我可以给你回电话吗？
But if you want to be really polite and you want to do it well then you should instead of just saying
但是，如果您想真正有礼貌并且想做得好，那么您应该而不是仅仅说
can I call you back.
我再打回给你可以吗。
Give us specific time say when you will call them back but don't state it as a positive thing like I
给我们具体的时间，说你什么时候给他们回电话，但不要像我一样把它说成是积极的事情
will do this.
会这样做。
Make sure to confirm it because if I say I will call you back in five minutes maybe you're not free
一定要确认一下，因为如果我说我会在五分钟内给你回电话，也许你没空
in five minutes so it's better to confirm with a question.
在五分钟内，所以最好用一个问题来确认。
So I'm.
所以我。
We could say I'm a bit tied up at the moment now to be very polite could I.
我们可以说我现在有点拘束以非常有礼貌，可以吗？
Or can I call you back.
或者我可以给你回电话吗？
Call you back in 10 minutes.
10分钟后给你回电话。
Can I call you back in 10 minutes.
我可以在 10 分钟后给你回电话吗？
This is a very polite way and a very common way to make sure the other person would be free at that
这是一种非常有礼貌的方式，也是一种非常常见的方式来确保对方在这方面有空
time.
时间。
If you just say Can I call you back and you don't say when.
如果你只是说我可以给你回电话，而你不说什么时候。
That makes the other person feel like you never will call them back.
这让对方觉得你永远不会给他们回电话。
If you say I will call you back in 10 minutes then the other person feels like you don't care about
如果你说我会在 10 分钟内给你回电话，那么对方会觉得你不在乎
their time you don't respect their time so do it this way.
他们的时间你不尊重他们的时间所以这样做。
Could I call you back in 10 minutes or is is it okay if I call you back in 15.
我可以在 10 分钟后给您回电话吗，或者我可以在 15 分钟内给您回电话吗？
Sometimes you just say 15 and we don't even say minutes because it can't be seconds and it can't be
有时你只说 15 而我们甚至不说分钟，因为它不可能是秒，也不可能是
hours right.
小时吧。
We know it's minutes.
我们知道这是分钟。
Can I call you back in 15.
我可以在 15 号给你回电话吗？
Yeah sure.
好，当然。
And I can just say sure sure means yes of course.
我只能说当然是肯定的意思是肯定的。
OK so that's a very common way to make sure the other person is free before you actually do the invitation.
好的，这是在您实际发出邀请之前确保对方空闲的一种非常常见的方法。
It's sort of like step two step one small talk step to make sure the other person is able to spend the
这有点像第二步一小步，以确保对方能够花费
couple minutes talking with you on the phone.
几分钟和你通电话。
It's pretty polite then when they want to know what you're calling about.
当他们想知道你在说什么时，这是非常有礼貌的。
If you don't say it you should say it.
如果你不说，你应该说。
You should say why you're calling.
你应该说你为什么打电话。
Yeah yeah I'm free.
是的，是的，我自由了。
Then you should say it but they might also say what's up.
那么你应该说出来，但他们也可能会说发生了什么。
Now this What's up means Why are you calling me so you could say are you free to talk now.
现在这怎么了意味着你为什么打电话给我，所以你可以说你现在有空说话。
Yeah I'm free to talk or Yeah I can talk.
是的，我可以自由交谈，或者是的，我可以交谈。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
Why are you calling me.
你为什么给我打电话。
It would be weird to say why are you calling me so we'll say instead.
说你为什么打电话给我会很奇怪，所以我们会说。
What's up.
这是怎么回事。
Then we get to the actual invitation.
然后我们得到实际的邀请。